今天对我们的星球来说是一个暗淡的周年纪念日。
Today marks a bleak anniversary for our planet.
自从三年前第一例植物病毒发现后
Three years ago the first case of a global plant virus was reported,
一场瘟疫便开始席卷并摧毁了几乎全部的生态系统
which started to ravage most of our ecosystems.
世界领先的研究实验室
The world's leading research laboratories
...曾经努力着试图阻止这个致命病毒的扩散
have been trying to find a way to stop this deadly pathogen,
但到目前为止，他们都没有成功。
but so far their efforts have been unsuccessful.
最近的研究表明，食用受病毒污染食物的人...
The latest research shows that people who consume food infected with a virus
...自身也将产生严重的自身免疫性疾病。
develop severe autoimmune diseases.
此外，大量减少的植物将会影响大气中的氧气含量。
In addition, the loss of plant life has contributed to the concentration
...大气中的氧气浓度达到 18%，
of oxygen in the atmosphere to decrease to 18%.
创历史新低。
The lowest on record.
迅速消失的森林无法维持氧循环的平衡
The rapidly disappearing forest cannot recycle
...这样的低氧水平将会长期存在
enough carbon dioxide to maintain these level for much longer.
这些大气变化导致世界范围内自然灾害的增加。
These atmospheric changes have caused an increase in natural disasters around the globe.
当氧气含量低于 10% 时，人们就会开始窒息。
As oxygen levels drop below 10%, people will begin to suffocate.
我们美丽的地区家园将要毁灭。
Our beautiful planet Earth is doomed.
但人类仍有生存的机会。
But humanity still has a chance of survival.
我们最大的希望，由史蒂文罗斯博士开发的双子座计划。
And their best hope is Project Gemini developed by Dr. Steven Ross.
该项目起源于8年前的一项考古发现一群古生物学家
The project centers around an archaeological find discovered eight years ago by a group of paleontologists
发现了两件奇特的物体与外星起源相关联
who found two unique objects of extraterrestrial origin.
这些文物估计有超过 40 亿年的历史。
The artifacts were estimated to be more than four billion years old.
斯蒂芬霍金曾经说过...
Stephen Hawking once said,
...如果人类想要长久的生存下去...
that if humans are to survive long term,
...就必须找到离开地球的方法。
we must find a way to get off planet Earth.
他对我们的机遇相当乐观
He was optimistic about our chances,
结果也证明他是对的
and in fact, as it turns out he was right.
这些奇特物件比生命本身更早出现在地球上。
These unique devices that we found appeared on Earth before life itself.
我们不知道是什么外星高等智慧创造了它们并将它们留在这里......
We don't know what mysterious Stellar wisdom created them and left them here,
...但我们在濒临灭亡时收到这些礼物。
but we've received this gift on the brink of extinction.
我们试图逆向研究这球体和引擎的材料
We managed to recreate this pseudo tough materials**
...然后成功地重建了它。
that the Sphere and the Engine are made of.
而且我们完美地复制了这两件物件。
And we precisely copied both of the devices.
现在我们拥有两件完全一样的设备。
Now each of them has an identical twin.
引擎用于星际飞行船舶的发动机。
The Warp Engine for interstellar flights
使我们能够找到一颗几乎适合地球化的行星。
has allowed us to find a planet more or less suitable for terraforming.
我们的无人卫星对系外行星TESS进行勘测
The unmanned vehicle completed a jump to the solar system TESS
...那些传回来的资料和样本证实了我们的理论
and returned with information and samples that confirmed our theories.
而这个球体,是用来创造生命的
And this device, this Sphere is for creating life.
经过多年的研究，我们发现了一种控制这球体和引擎的方法。
After years of research,we discovered a way to control the Sphere and the Engine.
这些物体有他们自己的语言。
These devices have their own unique language.
我们已经解码了几十条命令，
We decoded dozens of commands,
每条命令对应一个特定的模式。
each of which corresponds to a certain pattern.
这道初始命令对应的模式
This pattern gave the initial command,
球体曾经连续执行了40亿年
and the Sphere began to carry out more than four billion years now.
它利用环境中的化学元素开始创造真正的奇迹：
The Sphere uses chemical elements from the environment and creates a true miracle:
生命
life!
我们现在知道地球上的生命是由这台机器创造的。
Now we know life on Earth was created by this machine.
这个球体是我们计划的起点。
The Sphere is our starting point.
让我向您介绍我们一群领先的研究科学家的团队
Let me introduce you to our team of leading research scientists.
我们团队的成员有：彼得雷曼 博士。
Our team consists of: Dr. Peter Lehmann,
外星飞船引擎专家。
a specialist in extraterrestrial Warp Engine.
莱昂娜·雷德伍德 博士。
Doctor Leona Redwood,
地球化计划创始人。
a terraforming program builder.
今天加入我们的是由瑞安康纳少校军事训练过的飞行员们。
Today we are joined by military trained pilots,headed by Major Ryan Connor.
我们正在前往太阳系外行星的路上。
We are departing for the solar system TESS,
距离这里几百光年的地方。
several hundred light years from here.
我们将在适当的条件下将球体带到行星上。
We will bring The Sphere to a planet that has the right conditions.
带来我们的地球 2.0。
And we'll create Earth 2.0,
人类的新家园。
a new home for humanity.
双子座计划
你怎么看，彼得？
What do you think, Peter?
创造这些的家伙现在在哪里？
Whoever created this, where are they now?
没有足够的数据可以说明。
There's not enough data to say.
而且我不喜欢猜测这些事情。
And I don't really like speculating about stuff like this.
这不是毫无根据的猜测。 这是有依据的理论。
This isn't about the speculation.It's a theory.
也许来自一个失落的文明。
Maybe it was a lost civilization.
在高度发达文明中自我毁灭掉了……
We know from experience how highly-developed civilizations are good at self-destruction.
谁知道呢?     是的。
-Who knows?  -Yeah.
对人类来说，这算是一次飞跃了，对吧？
Well, another giant leap for humanity, eh, guys?
历史上第一次巨大进步。
Only this time literally,for the first time in history.
只要比一团原子多的东西, 就能成为我们未来的家园
Just as long as something more than a bunch of atoms makes it to the destination…
那也算是了。
It still counts.
说啊,历史上的第一次。
Say it. For the first time in history.
注意了，准备空间跳跃。
Attention! And prepare for a jump.
所有系统已就绪。
All systems are ready.
坐标已设置。
The coordinates are set.
空间引擎设置为最大功率
Warp Drive set at maximum power.
准备？
Ready?
开始
Engage.
致命错误。
Critical error.
我们在哪？
Where are we?
这是TESS吗？
Is this TESS?
理查德，我们达到指定位置了吗？
Richard, did we complete the maneuver?
是的，我们到了。
Yes, we did.
星图...并不匹配。
Star maps…They don't match up.
这不是TESS。
It's not TESS.
什么坐标，你投进去了吗？
What coordinates.did you put in?
你确定你输入了正确的坐标?
Are you sure they were operational?
当然，长官。
Of course, sir.
你检查过引擎吗？
Did you check the Engine?
一切都按照计划进行。
Everything was done according to protocol.
如果一切都按照计划来...
If everything was done to protocol,
...我们现在就应该在 TESS。
we'd be in TESS right now.
任务失败了，彼得。
The mission failed, Peter.
地球已经没有希望了。
There is no hope for Earth now.
- 请求许可检查引擎？               - 不。
-Permission to check the Engine.   -No.
你渎职了。
You are relieved of your duties.
回到在你的休息室直到我另有命令。
Stay in your bunk until I say otherwise.
是, 长官。
Yes, sir.
这是什么？
What's this?
在物理......有一个方程称为狄拉克方程。
In physics,there is an equation… The Dirac equation.
当两个粒子相互接触，
When two particles come into contact,
它们将永远彼此相连系。
they become bound forever.
尽管将他们分隔数光年，他们仍然"感受"着彼此。
They continue to "feel" one another,even if they are light years apart.
这被称为量子纠缠。
It's called quantum entanglement.
所以这对你来说是物理学?
That's physics for you?
这不仅仅是物理学。
Not just physics.
尝试调整跳跃轨迹。
Try de-set the jump trajectory.
也许这会让我们知道我们的位置。
Maybe it will help us figure out where we are.
不，史蒂夫。轨迹不清晰。
No, Steve.The trajectory is not clear.
数据没有任何意义。
The data doesn't make any sense at all.
我们好像进入了第四维度
We've entered the fourth dimension,
但又好像是移动了坐标轴一样,我们无法到达目的地……
But it's almost as if we moved along the coordinates axis that we can't access.
然后我们又跳回了三维空间。
And then we jumped back into three-dimensional space.
但我们现在在哪里？
But where?
我们的环境中有什么东西可以帮助我们找到自己的位置吗？
Is there anything around us that can help us figure out our location?
不, 没有参照物。也没有什么是已知的。
No, no land marks.Nothing even remotely familiar.
我们没有任何数据可以跳回去。
We have no point to set a return jump.
什么意思？
So that means
直到我们知道我们在哪里之前我们没法回去。
that until we figure out where we are we can't get back.
确实。
No.
"维修气闸打开"
Repair airlock is open.
这是什么？
What's that?
发动机区域的维修气闸打开了。
The repair airlock of the Engine compartment is open.
什么情况？ 有人在那吗？
Why? And who is there?
气闸，回复,这里是船长。 气闸那有人的话请回答。
Repair airlock, this is the captain calling. Airlock, report.
"不明物体接近"
Unidentified object approaching.
妈的！
Shit!
这些都是啥破事啊
I can't believe it.
冷静点，蕾欧娜。
Calm down, Leona.
想活下来的话，我们必须保持冷静。
We gotta keep our cool if we wanna survive.
我们已经失去了一名队友。
We are already a man down.
彼得无视史蒂夫的命令，去了发动机区。
Peter ignored Steve's orders,went to the Engine compartment,
他认为他把我们带到了错误的地方，然后他结束了自己的生命。
realised what he'd done,and that was the end.
彼得不会那样做！
Peter wouldn't have.
我了解他！
I knew him.
我和他一起工作了8年！
I worked with him for eight years.
他不会那么轻易放弃的！
He couldn't given up so easily.
莱昂，够了！
Leona, enough.
不该是这样为他求情的！
How can you defend him?
现在我们必须处理他造成的错误后果。
Now we have to deal with the results of his mistakes.
做他本该做好的工作。
Do his work for him.
一个人把我们全体拖下水。
One person put multiple lives in danger.
他几乎摧毁了人类唯一的生存机会！
He almost destroyed humanity's only chance of survival.
这才应该是你流泪的理由
That's who you should be crying for?
丽塔死后，我也不想活了。
After Rita died I didn't wanna live anymore.
然后我想了比起一了百了
But then I thought,instead of ending it all
我还可以做一些有意义的事情。
I could make it mean something.
所以我决定全身心地投入到这项任务中。
So I decided to devote myself to the mission.
但事实证明...
But now it turns out
现在的我比在地球上更无能。
that I'm less useful here than on Earth.
大卫。
David…
一切都会好的,  我们总会有办法的。
Everything will be all right.We'll find a way out this.
地球的未来就靠我们的任务成败与否。
The future of Earth depends on our mission.
放弃不是我们的选择。
Giving up is not an option.
我们必须确定我们在哪维宇宙。
We need to establish what part of the universe we're in.
-理查德，你知道什么些吗？
-Richard, do you have anything?
-还没有。
-Not yet.
我跟踪最近的恒星和行星的运动轨迹。
I'm tracking the moving trajectories of the nearest stars and planets.
以此试着计算我们的位置。
I'll try to calculate our position from there.
大卫。那颗星球怎么样？
David, what about that planet?
传感器有数据吗？
Any data on the probe?
刚刚接收。
Just loaded.
好的。
Great.
这颗行星的表面是由火山岩组成的。
The surface of the planet is made of volcanic rock.
没有生命。
有大气但没有氧气。
There is an atmosphere,but without oxygen.
平均温度为16摄氏度。
The average temperature is 16 degrees Celsius.
外部环境也对人也不算危险。
The outside environment isn't aggressive.
我们需要的只是呼吸器。
All we'll need are breathing masks.
那不错啊。
It's perfect.
如果我必须在TESS和这个星球之间做出选择……
If I could choose between TESS and this planet,
...我也许会去这里。
I'd go here.
你知道我们有多幸运吗？
Do you realize how lucky we are?
找到适合球体的行星的几率有多大？
What was the likelihood of winding up near planet that's perfect for the Sphere?
如果这不是意外呢？
What if this isn't an accident?
我是说如果我们是被引导到这里的怎么办？
What if we were brought here on purpose?
谁会这么做？   "他们",和"他们"给我们留下了球体不是一回事吗?
-By whom?       -The same thing that left us the Sphere.
瑞恩，准备登陆星球。                你什么意思？
-Ryan, get ready to disembark.   -What do you mean?
我们可以在这个星球上完成我们的使命。
We can complete our mission on this planet.
但我们还没有检查过它。
But we haven't examined it.
但这是我们仅有的机会。
But this is our chance.
如果我们将球体发射到这个星球上...
If we launch the Sphere on this planet
我们也有足够的时间去搞清楚我们在哪。
we'll have enough time to understand where we are.
这样，其他舰船就可以跃迁到我们这来。
Then, other ships come repeat our job.
理查德，准备着陆器降落在这个星球上。
Richard, prepare the lander to go down to the planet.
但这是一颗年轻的星球。 大气不稳定。
But it's a young planet,the atmosphere is unstable.
我们对这个星球一无所知。
We don't know anything about it.
降落在地面上可能不安全。
It might not be safe to make a surface landing.
我同意。 你鲁莽地冒着船员安全风险。
I agree, you're recklessly risking the safety of the crew.
我反对。
And I'm against it.
幸运的是，我是做出最终决定的人。
Thankfully, I am the one who makes the final decisions.
不，史蒂夫，现在做出这样的决定还为时过早。
No, Steve. It's too early for decisions like these.
我说我们要着陆。
I said we are landing.
理查德。 告诉我着陆点。
Richard, show in the landing area.
你们将要在这里着陆，在峡谷里。
You'll land here, in the valley.
在那里是着陆是天气条件最好的。
The weather conditions for descent are optimal.
行了, 开始分离程序。
We're ready.Initiate un-docking procedure.
"开始分离程序"。
Un-docking sequence initiated.
"引擎启动"
Engine's activated.
"高度30,000 米。 下降中"
The height is 30,000 meters. Coming down.
一场风暴正在靠近。
A storm front is heading your way.
这风暴几分钟前才形成的，没法预测。
It formed a few minutes ago.Couldn't have predicted it.
风速每秒 40 米
The winds are up to 40 meters per second.
各位稳住咯。减速喷射器启动。
So hold on.Activating braking thrusters.
卧槽怎么回事？
What the hell was that?
外面怎么了？                      风暴。
- What's going on?   -It's the wind.
雷暴好像相当猛烈。
The storm is quite aggressive.
我们以两倍的下降速度移动。 我们正在坠落！
The descent is twice as high as the landing speed. We're falling.
这样我们会坠毁在星球表面上！
We're gonna crush into surface.
我可以加倍喷射速度，可以降低你们的下降速度。
I can double the thrust.It will slow your fall.
但如果我们这样做，我们就没有燃料飞回去了！
If we use that we won't have a fuel for the return flight!
如果不这样做，我们也会死。
If we don't, we will die!
温度太高了。你们的飞船外壳正在融化。
The temperature is too extreme. Your hole is melting.
操！ 把第一罐燃料用了吧！
Damn it!Release the first tank.
我正在试着以改变姿态的方式减速。
I'll try to slow you down aerodynamically.
希望这飞船能撑得住。
I hope the hole holds up.
抓稳了！接近地面!
Hold on.We are coming in on it!
准备撞击！
Brace for impact!
艾米？
Amy…
艾米……你这是要去哪？
Amy, why did you fly off to?
我需要你。
I need you.
我给你带了点东西。
I got you something.
这是什么？
What's this?
我们在一起一年了。
We've been together for a year.
你知道，这"球体"对我来说意义重大。
You know, The Sphere means a lot to me,
但远比不上你在我心中的地位。
but not as much as you do.
老实说，我知道你们两个不太处。
Obviously, I know you two don't get along.
这就是为什么我想创造一些连接你们俩的东西。
So I thought to create something to connect you both.
这是原来"球体"的一部分。
It's made out of the old Sphere.
它曾经是一块碎片,但也十分奇特。
There was a fragment that really stood out.
挺漂亮的。 谢谢你。
It's so beautiful. Thank you.
我觉得这是一种象征。
I thought it would be symbolic.
"球体"是人类的救赎的途径。
The Sphere is our salvation,
而你也是我的救赎。
and you are mine.
我们回家吧。 草坪洒水器准备开始喷水了。
Let's go home. The sprinklers are about to start spraying.
再待一会吧。
Let's stay for a while.
飞船状况如何？没有受到致命损伤
-What's the status on the lander? No critical damage.
但燃料快用完了。
But it's almost out of fuel.
现在没法回到船上，我们被困在这里。
Now we can't get back to the ship,we're stuck here.
为什么要回到船上？
Why go back to the ship?
我们 4 年内才回去。
Our plan was to come back in four years.
现在我们的主要任务是设置和初始化"球体"。
And now our main task is to install and launch the Sphere.
我们继续这个计划。
We're continuing the program.
但现在我们没法继续我们的计划。
But we can't carry it out now.
我们在山谷里,离计划着陆区太远了。
We strayed too far away from the landing site, into the mountains.
这意味着这里一定有洞穴。
That means there should be caves here.
然而，在这样的地形上是不可能放置穹顶的。
But it's impossible to deploy domes on this terrain.
没有穹顶也能完成我们的计划。
We'll manage without domes.
一个足够深的洞穴将为球体提供恰到好处的保护。
A deep enough cave will provide the right amount of protection for the Sphere.
这里，这个洞穴看起来很合适。
There! This cave looks suitable.
它够大而且很近。
It's big enough and easy to access.
Leona，获取地震活动数据。
Leona, you get the data on seismic activity,
大卫，调整计划。
David, adjust the program.
其他人, 检查装备。
Everyone else, check the equipment.
动身吧，伙计们。 还在等什么？
Get to work, people,what are you waiting for?
这个星球上的条件比我们预期的还要好。
Conditions on this planet are even better than we expected.
其他船只很快就会来到这里。
Other ships will arrive here soon.
人类的新历史从这一刻开始。
A new history of mankind begins here,at this very minute.
我们做到了，真是难以置信。
We did it! I can't believe it.
如果彼得看到了这些, 他会很高兴的。他为此努力了太多。
Peter would be so happy.He worked so hard for this.
船长，你应该看看这个。
Captain, you need to see this.
他本应该在这里。
He should be here.
好的，注意了船员们。
Okay, attention, team.
我们现在返回基地。
We're returning to base.
走吧。
Move out.
大卫,  我们有数据吗？
David, do you have any data?
还没有。
Not yet.
罗斯医生，军事法现在在这个驻地生效。
Doctor Ross, martial lawsare in effect on this station.
啥？ 为什么？
What? Why?
我们有新的消息。
We have new information.
理查德？
Richard?
开始播放。
Starting playback.
这里是 彼得雷曼 博士。
This is Dr. Peter Lehmann.
很抱歉我违反命令，独自检查发动机。
Against all orders, I will personally conduct an Engine inspection.
我将记录我的所有操作
I'm now recording all of my actions
以免我受到无关的指责。
so I'm not accused of tampering with the results.
安全摄像头已关闭所以没人可以干扰到我。
The security cameras are switched off so that I am not interrupted.
我不会成为替罪羊。
I'm not gonna be a scapegoat.
我会证明我没有犯错。
I'm gonna prove that I made no mistake.
救命！
Help!
那是什么鬼东西？
What was that?
某种生命？
Some kind of a life form?
就是那玩意杀死彼得的吗？
Was that what killed Peter?
我看了所有的监控记录。
I watched all of the recordings from the cameras.
它就出现在球体旁边。
It shows up by the Sphere for the first time
自从我们离开地球后
right after we left Earth.
那东西是不是从球体里跑出来了？
This thing crawled out of the Sphere?
什么特洛伊木马故事。
Straight outta the story of the Trojan horse.
而那个特洛伊木马就在飞船跃迁之前爬进了引擎。
And that Trojan climbed right into the Engine just before the jump.
那么我们跃迁失败就是那玩意造成的？
So maybe it caused the failure?
理查德，那如果那个"特洛伊"还在船上，那你就有危险了。
Richard, if that Trojan is still on the ship, you're in danger.
不, 它和你一起下去了。
No. He went down with you,
进到了"球体"里面。
into the Sphere.
我们可以追踪"它"的位置。
We can track its position.
这东西对电磁场有干扰。
It causes interference in the electromagnetic field.
这是相机在着陆前录制的视频。
Here's the video from the cameras right before the landing.
我从洞穴中得到了最初的数据。
I've got the first data from the cave.
有什么不正常的，史蒂夫?
Something's strange. Steve?
"球体"内的二氧化碳和氧化作用正在上升，
Levels of CO2 and oxidation inside the Sphere are rising,
但是没有生命的迹象。
but there aren't any bio markers.
什么？会不会出故障了？
What? Could it be a malfunction?
不，它正在满负荷运行。
No, it's working in a full capacity.
它运行了和我们预期不同的程序。
Just on the different program than the one we've uploaded.
它...它正在做其他事情。
It's doing something else.
整队。
Regroup.
我们要回到"球体"那。 我们需要改变设置。
We're going back to the Sphere.We need to adjust the settings.
史蒂夫，没人会离开。
Nobody's going anywhere, Steve.
在消除了威胁之后，我们会进行处理程序的问题。
We'll adjust the settings later,after we deal with the threat.
但史蒂夫是该项目的负责人，他发号施令。
But Steve is the head of the project,he calls the shots.
不再是了。
Not anymore.
从现在开始，一切都是为了船员的生存。
Now it's a question of the crew survival.
史蒂夫，现在我指挥，你被架空了。
Steve, I'm taking command,you're being relieved.
你不能这样！
You can't do that.
这个任务决定着人类的未来！
The future of mankind depends on this mission.
只有罗斯 博士 可以弄明白！
Only Dr. Ross can carry it out.
你确定罗斯博士老实告诉了我们
Are you sure that Dr. Ross is giving us all the information
这个"球体"到底是什么了吗?
about what the Sphere actually is?
你什么意思？
What are you talking about?
理查德, 给我看洞穴的录像。
Richard, show the video from the cave.
史蒂夫看到了异常。
Steve saw the anomaly.
而且他没有告诉其他人。
And didn't say anything to anyone
他全体船员的生命危险置于危险而不顾。
risking the lives of the entire crew.
哪儿来的呢？                  来自那个"球体"。
-Where did it come from?     -Right from the Sphere.
事实证明，我们对"球体"知之甚少。
Which as it turns out we know too little about.
如果它是某种怪物的孵化器呢？
What if it's an incubator for those monsters?
对于"球体"的真相我对你没有任何隐瞒。
I didn't hide a single confirmed fact about the Sphere from you.
现在讨论这些异常没有意义。
And there was no sense in discussing anomalies.
如果我们知道这些异常
If we had known about these anomalies,
我们就不会以这样的方式处理"球体"。
we would have treated the Sphere differently,
而且彼得现在应该还活着。
and Peter would be alive right now.
大卫，很抱歉我没能成功。
David, I'm sorry I couldn't make it.
没关系。
It's okay.
我知道你很忙。
I understand how busy you are.
对, 我们也没有时间可以浪费。
Yes, we don't have much time to spare.
你在这干啥？
Why are you here?
医生说我没事。 他给了我健康报告。
The doctor says I'm fine.Gave me a clean bill of health.
所以我准备好加入预发射团队。
So I'm ready to join everyone for the pre-launch.
什么？
What?
那么你...
I mean you…
你真的打算加入这个计划吗？
You're actually planning to fly?
是你让我成为船员。
But you are the one who made me a member of the crew.
但那是之前的事了...
But that was before…
丽塔去世前？ 所以呢？
Before Rita died?
我告诉你，心理学家证实我很好。
So what?I'm telling you the psychologist has confirmed I'm okay.
但你的女儿...
But to lose a daughter…
大卫，我很抱歉。
David, I'm terribly sorry.
我知道你想回去工作，
I understand you want to get back to work
但这不是忘记悲伤的最好方法,
but this is not the best way.
你现在需要时间缅怀。
Right now you need time to grief.
史蒂夫，我不是为了忘记我的女儿而飞。
Steve, I'm not flying to forget my daughter.
我的女儿永远是我的一部分。
She'll always be a part of me.
我和你一样了解"球体"。
I know the Sphere as well as you do.
在那里你会需要我。
And you'll need me there.
大卫,听着。
David, listen,
我所做的就是照顾你。
all I'm doing is looking out for you.
什么？
What?
你把我除名了?
You're crossing my name off?
在我们取得这一切之后，你就这样抛弃我？
After all we've done you're going to leave me on the sidelines?
我可以帮你改变未来。
I can help you change the future.
不要带走我的这个机会。
Don't take that away from me.
干啥？
-What?
我们不能就这么走了。
We can't leave it like that.
我们必须回到洞穴并恢复我们的目标设置。
We have to go back to the cave and restore the settings.
但瑞恩有命令。
-But Ryan gave orders.
就我俩。
-Just you and me.
我们悄悄地去。
We'll go out quietly.
杀死了彼得的那玩意还在那儿。
Whatever killed Peter is still in there.
"特洛伊"目前距离洞穴 30 公里远。
The Trojan is 30 kilometers away from the cave right now,
这意味着如果那"东西"要回来......
that means if it decides to come back
我们至少还有半个小时撤离。
we'll have at least half an hour to get out.
- 瑞恩呢？
-What about Ryan?
- 瑞恩谨慎过度了。
-Ryan's too careful.
他在浪费时间！
He's wasting time.
时间就是生命。
Lost days are lost lives.
丽塔去世后，你的一部分也随着丽塔逝去。
When Rita was dying,you slowly died with her.
我知道那是怎么样的感觉。
I saw what that was like.
现在想象我们的家园以同样的方式死亡。
Now imagine that entire planet is dying the exact same way.
慢慢地，不可逆转的毁灭，因为同一种病毒。
Slowly, irreversibly,from the same virus.
我草这是什么？
What the hell is this?
怎么了？
What's going on?
这些都是"球体"干的。
The Sphere did this.
你认为这是故障吗？
-You think it was a malfunction?
这不止是故障。
-Not just a malfunction
"球体"创造了一种外星生命形式。
The Sphere is creating an alien life form.
而且相当快。
And incredibly quickly.
比它在地球上创造生命的速度还要快。
Faster than it created life on Earth.
我们不该碰它，应该和所有人都讨论一下。
We shouldn't touch it.We need to discuss this with everybody.
我们需要制定一个行动计划。
We need to set a plan of action.
有人调整了"球体"的设置。
Someone readjusted the settings on the Sphere.
"特洛伊"正在逼近。 我们该走了！
The Trojan's getting closer,we gotta leave.
在等一会。
Just a minute.
你没听见吗？
Can't you hear me?
这犯不着你拿命去赌。 快走！
There's no point in risking our lives!Let's go!
离我远点！ 该死的！
Get away from me, dammit!
你疯了吗？
Have you lost your mind?
完了！ 任务失败！
It's over! The mission is over!
承认吧！
Deal with it!
"球体"有敌意！
The Sphere is hostile!
放下枪，大卫！ 快放下！
Put the gun down, David! Put it down!
你想为这个垃圾玩意去死？
You wanna die because of this piece of shit?
太迟了, 它已经在发展了。
Too late, it's already here.
"气闸关闭"
Airlock closed.
"加压完成"
Pressurization completed.
你他妈真是疯了，史蒂夫。 因为你，我们差点死了。
You're a psycho, Steve.Because of you, we both almost died.
这不关我们的事。我们必须得完成任务。
This is not about us.We have to complete the mission.
如果你损坏了"球体"，我们一切努力都将付诸东流。
If you had damaged the Sphere all of this would've been for nothing.
那你就该开枪打死我！那你为什么不呢？
Then you should've shot me.Why didn't you?
如果你再次危及任务...
If you threaten the mission one more time
我会的。
I will.
史蒂夫，你在做什么？你去哪儿了？
Steve, what the hell were you doing?Where were you?
你为什么违背我的命令离开着陆器？
Why did you leave the lander against my orders?
我们做了我们必须做的。
We did what we had to.
你没有权利指挥我们。
You no longer have the right to make decisions.
我做了我认为该做的事。
I make the decisions I find necessary.
不然呢？
Or what?
你你会怎么做？暴力？
What are you gonna do?Use force?
那来啊!
Then go ahead! Well?
来打啊!
Come on!
"模块完整性错误"
Module integrity compromised.
你做了什么？
What did you do?
"模块完整性错误"
Module integrity compromised.
安静点，亲爱的。
Quiet, sweetie.
我们差点失去理智。
We're so close I'm losing my head.
那是什么？
What's that?
"特洛伊"已经进来了。
Trojan's in the lander.
他接管了我们的系统，我们有大麻烦了。
Got a hole in the lower deck,everything's covered in this shit.
那么，我们现在该怎么办？
So what do we do now?
静谧行动,走吧
Quietly, and slowly. Let's go.
喘不上气啊。
It's hard to breathe.
回去吧。
Get back.
哈？ 为什么？
What? Why?
"他"在这儿。
It's here.
快跑。
Run!
怎么回事？ 你俩还好吗？
What's happened?Are you okay?
"特洛伊"!
The Trojan…
"特洛伊"在实验室！
The Trojan's in the laboratory.
你知道你俩做了什么蠢事吗？
Do you realize what you've done?
你把那玩意带下来了！
You brought it down here with you!
它能进来吗？
-Can it get in here?
我们没法知道。
-We don't know.
它损坏了发电机，摄像机无法工作。
It damaged the generator and the cameras aren't working.
我们与母舰失去了联系。
We've lost contact with the ship, so…
我们无法得到太空传来的录像！
We have no video from space.
这是系统中录制的最后一个视频。
Here's the last video saved on the system.
这东西正在寻找船体的薄弱处。
It was looking for a weak spot in the hull.
它进入了冷却系统。
It got in through the cooling system.
那里的钢板最薄。
Where the steel is thinnest.
所以这个东西有智慧?它会思考?
So this thing is smart?It can think?
不管它有没有脑子……
Whether it can think or not,
如果我们把它熏出去把洞给补上，它就不能再爬进来了。
if we smoke it out and with the hole shut it can't crawl back in.
但该怎么做？ 我们如何把它弄出来？
But how? How can we smoke it out?
我们甚至不知道它在哪。
We can't even see where it is.
我们需要重启安全摄像头和通讯。
We have to restore the security cameras and communications.
"特洛伊"损坏了主发电机。但是维生系统仍然在工作。
The Trojan damaged the main generator,but the life support system is working.
这意味着备用发电机没有坏。
That means the back up generator is fine.
我们可以将网络和摄像头连接到备用电机。
We can connect the network and cameras to it.
我们一路摸黑保险丝盒那！
We will have to make all the way blind to the fuse box
而且不知道这狗杂种在哪里
with no idea where that bastard is.
这太冒险了。
It's too risky.
都是我的错。
It's all my fault.
那我去。
So I'll go.
我会掩护你背后。
I'll watch your six.
史蒂夫！
Steve,
快离开那里, 现在！
you need to get out of there, now!
受伤了吗？
Are you hurt?
信号和摄像头怎么样？
How's the signal and the cameras?
一切正常，重新上线。
All there. Back online.
该死，它发射的电磁场比球体还要强！
Damn it! It's transmitting an EMP field stronger than the Sphere.
它旁边的那些电子设备要坏了。
The electronics next to it are going crazy.
现在怎么办？
So what now?
你曾经见过一头愤怒的公牛追逐那些奔跑的人们吗？
Have you ever seen a raging bull running after the crowds
在人牛正式对决之前, 有一条狭窄的巷子
down a narrow passage just before a bull fight?
愤怒的公牛想要逮住那些逃跑的人
The bull wants to catch the runners,
但巷子最终会将公牛和斗牛士在带到竞技场上对决。
but he ends up in the arena with the matador.
现在"特洛伊"就是那头公牛。他也想抓住我们。
The Trojan is the bull.It also wants to catch us.
我们有机会将它带到任何我们想要的地方，例如在着陆器外。
We have a chance to lead it wherever we want, like outside the lander.
每个人都承受着巨大的风险。
It's a huge risk for everyone,
但这将是值得的。
but it's all worth it.
着陆器有 2 个气闸。
The lander has two airlocks:
在一个在中心另一个在实验室。
the central one, and the one in the lab.
我会在在中央舱门前的外边。
I'll be outside in front of the open central hatch.
我做主要诱饵。
I'll be the main decoy.
"特洛伊"会追着我穿过走廊。
The Trojan will chase me along the corridors.
一旦我们到了外面，你要关闭它身后的引擎气闸。
Once we get outside, you'll shut the engines to the airlock behind it.
明白了吗？
Understood?
但要做到这一切，我们必须去气闸。
But in order to do all that,we need to get to the airlocks.
这就是"特洛伊"所在的地方。
And that's where the Trojan is.
我们可以把它孤立在主走廊里, 这.
We can isolate it in the main corridor, here.
内部舱门没法关住它太久。
The inner doors won't hold on long,
但应该为能我们争取一些时间。
but should buy us some time.
我会将它引入内盖所在的区域并把他锁在那里。
I'll lure him into the inter-hatch space.And lock him in
在"特洛伊"被关起来后，我们每个人都要到特定的地点。
After the Trojan is blocked, each one of us will report to a specific location.
大卫，你和我将打开实验室的气闸。
David, you and I will open the air hatch in the labs.
当我出去引诱"特洛伊"时，你在那里等我。
You'll wait for me there,while I'll go outside to be the bait for the Trojan.
但是为了确保"特洛伊"看到我并出来...
But in order for the Trojan to see me and come out
两侧的气闸都必须打开。
both sides of the airlock have to be open,
外面和里面的。
outside and inside.
所以 Leona 得手动打开气闸。
That's why Leona will manually open the airlock
然后就躲在科技仓那。
and hide right here,in the technical bay.
当特洛伊追上我时，它会跑到这里。
When the Trojan comes after me,it will run over here,
穿过发动机喷嘴。
past the Engine's steering nozzles.
应该还剩有一些燃料。
There should be some fuel left.
如果我们在正确的时刻启动引擎...
And if we turn the Engine at the right moment
...我们不只是把它轰出去，我们烤熟他。
we won't just smoke it out,we'll roast it.
滚开，这该死的混蛋！
Get out of here, you fucking bastard!
动作快！ 这门要坚持不住了。
Hurry! It won't hold up much longer!
别慌。 把"特洛伊"引导出来。
Don't panic. Release the Trojan.
好好躲在技术舱。
Hide in the tech bay.
你做得到。
You can do it.
我正在启动引擎。
I'm turning on the Engine.
引擎没有启动，"特洛伊"正扰乱乱系统！
It's not working.The Trojan is messing with the system.
史蒂夫，快跑！
Steve, run!
引擎启动了。
The Engine's on.
蕾欧娜，出去！ 快出去！
Leona, get out! Get out!
瑞恩，气闸！ 快关闭气闸！
Ryan, the airlock!Shut the airlock!
草。
Shit!
安息吧，弗兰克。
Rest in peace, Frank.
舱门切断了它的一部分触手。它回山洞去了。
A part of its tentacle was cut off by the door. It returned to the cave.
"加压完成"
Pressurization complete.
"氧气水平正在恢复正常"
Oxygen level returning to normal.
它回不来了。
It won't get back in here.
但那玩意控制"球体"了。
But the Sphere is under its control.
不会持续太久的。
Not for long.
艾米？
Amy.
这是什么？
What is it?
病毒。
It's the virus…
老实说.病毒已经在我们的家园之中了。
It's already in our home, literally.
你不应该去执行这个任务。
You shouldn't go on this mission.
艾米，你在胡说什么呢？我想我们已经都谈妥了。
Amy, what are you talking about?We discussed everything.
你已经做得够多的了，这不是你的任务。
You've done enough.This isn't your mission.
- 拜托.         - 你甚至都不是宇航员。
-Excuse me? -You're not even an astronaut.
你想让我在发射前一周离开？
You want me to walk out a week before the launch?
你怎么回事？
What's gotten into you?
我们要有孩子了。
We're going to have a baby.
什么？
What?
留下来吧,
Just stay.
疫苗也是我们的希望。我找到了一个有前途的方法！
We'll work on the vaccine.I found a promising pathway.
这任务将创造一个新地球，但我们也可以拯救我们的地球。
The mission will create a new Earth but we could save this one.
这是我疫苗的蓝图, 看看吧。
This is my blueprint for the vaccine,please go over it.
这让我真的很开心。
I'm really happy.
但是时间紧迫。
But it's such poor timing.
我也许没法看到我们的孩子成长了。
I won't get to see him grow up.
史蒂夫！ 我恳求你, 留在我身边，留在我们的身边！
Steve, I'm begging you.Please, stay with me. Stay with us.
对不起，我得去做我们的任务。我必须去的。
I can't, I have to be there. I have to.
你已经尽你所能了。
You've done everything you could.
我们可以开发疫苗，我认为这是有用的！
We can develop the vaccine now.I think I'm onto something.
我得拯救地球。
I need to save the Earth.
我们需要研究这种生物，
We have to study this creature,
这样我们才能了解你感染了什么。
so we can understand what you're infected with.
我猜它是一种生物机器。
My guess, it's a bio-robot.
他们与"球体"的材料相同。
These are the same materials the Sphere is made of.
当它们接触到水时，就会改变它们的特性。
And they also change their properties when they come into contact with water.
我们研究了它，但从未了解
We studied it never understanding
它的功能之一是创造"特洛伊"
that one of its functions was to create a Trojan.
也许它比我们先进得多。
Maybe they are much more advanced than we are.
而且更好。
And better.
大卫,听着。
David, listen…
告诉我你发现了什么。
Tell me what you found.
感染你的细菌...
The bacteria that infected you
...具有异常强大的防御机制。
have an unusually powerful defense mechanism.
经过我的调查，
I studied them.
我弄清楚了它的原理。
Figured out how they work.
这就是我们千辛万苦所寻找的。
This is what we spent all those years searching for.
你的血液就是制备对抗...
Your blood holds the key to the vaccine against the virus
摧毁我们家园病毒疫苗的关键
that's been destroying life on Earth.
这不会改变任何事情。
It doesn't change anything.
你还不明白吗？
Don't you understand?
我们可以拯救世界。
We can save the world.
而这一切是因为你。你是真正的英雄。
And it's all because of you.You are the real hero.
我会给你止痛药。你会感觉好点的。
I'll administer some painkillers,you'll feel better.
那就来吧。
Here goes nothing…
那是什么？
What was that?
大卫...
David…
这是个应答器。
It's a transponder.
我们可以看到这些与"球体"的联系。
We can see the connections of the Sphere.
这是他们殖民行星的方式。
This is their way of colonizing planets.
怎么回事？
How's it going?
这是一个生物机器人。
It's a bio-robot.
我们必须想办法摧毁它
We have to find a way to destroy it
并且重置"球体"。
and restore the settings in the Sphere.
不，史蒂夫。 已经有太多人因为你而死了。
No, Steve. Too many people have died because of you already.
等会,你做了什么？
Wait. What did you do?
你把我锁在里面了吗？
Did you lock me in?
你被捕了，史蒂夫。
You are under arrest, Steve.
瑞安...
Ryan,
我们必须共同努力.
we have to work together.
为了彼得、弗兰克和莱昂娜。
For Peter, and Frank and Leona.
否则，他们会白白死去。
Otherwise they all died in vain--
对你来说,同伴只不过是消耗品。
People are expendable to you.
瑞恩！ 瑞恩！ 瑞恩！
Ryan! Ryan!
他是对的。
He's right.
人类的救赎对你来说从来都不是重要的，史蒂夫。
It was never the salvation of humanity that was most important to you, Steve.
你一直想扮演英雄。
You always wanna play the hero.
而现在你想要的就是赢。你也不关心其他人的死活。
And now you just want to win and you don't care about other people's lives.
艾米，回答我。
Amy, talk to me.
我已经看过了你的提案。 它看起来真的很有希望。
I read your proposal.It looks truly promising.
一个真正的突破
A real breakthrough.
一个研制疫苗的机会,确实很有希望。
A chance to create a vaccine.Finally, a real one.
但我还是得去。为了我们好。
But I do need to go.For our sake.
没有你我不知道该怎么办。
I don't know what I'll do without you
我保证, 我会回来的。
but I promise I'll come back.
我需要你。
I need you.
你和我们的孩子。
Both of you.
告诉我们的儿子...
Tell him…
...或者我们的女儿...
or her…
...他的父亲将像上帝一样创造一个新地球。
that Daddy like a God is out creating the new Earth.
你总是这样说你为了拯救所有人才做的这些。
You keep saying you're doing this to save everyone.
但是每个人又是谁？
But who is everyone?
你现在目中无人。
You don't see people around you.
你只关心你自己, 和你的项目。有什么区别吗。
All you care about is you and your project. Why even bother?
你想被称赞为救世主吗？ 就这？
To be the hailed a savior? Is that it?
我想拯救我们的未来。
To save our future.
我不知道你真正想要拯救的是什么。
I wonder what it is you're really trying to save.
理查德，你模拟了过最近恒星的轨道吗？
Richard, you modeled the trajectories of the nearest stars?
那样做什么都得不到。你觉得那有可能找到些什么吗？
That didn't give us anything.What do you think you'll find there?
我们在跃迁时你说过:
You said that when we made the jump
你说我们沿着空间坐标轴穿越,然而这对我们来说是做不到的
we moved along a coordinate axis that was inaccessible to us.
如果这个轴不属于空间呢？
And what if that axis wasn't spatial?
让我们看看这些星星应该的样子
Show us how these stars will look
加入宇宙膨胀超过四十亿年的参数...
accounting the expansion of the universe over four billion years.
行, 重新计算中。
Yes, recalculating.
我们并没有穿越空间。
We didn't move in space.
而是穿越了时间。
We moved in time.
这是大熊座(北斗七星)。
It's Ursa Major.
和猎户座。
And Orion.
它就是 北极星。
And there's the North Star…
而我们的...
and our…
太阳？
Sun?
地球是一片死寂，
And the Earth was silent and empty,
地球的深渊里一片黑暗。
and the darkness over the abyss.
那意味着我们在地球上？
That means that we're on Earth?
在生命开始之前？
Before the beginning of life itself?
四十亿年前？
About four billion years ago.
你刚刚是怎么发现的？
How did you figure that out?
这是那块大卫开火时击落的碎片。
This is the fragment that flew off the Sphere when David fired at it.
从"球体"击飞出的。那块碎片.
Here is the broken fragment.
和我为艾米做的手镯碎片一模一样。
And here is the same pieceon the bracelet I made for Amy.
因为这就是同一片碎片。
Because it's the exact same fragment.
我们这里的"球体"和地球上的旧"球体"……
The Sphere here and the old one on Earth
...就是同一个"球体"。
are the exact same Sphere,
但是在不同的时间的同一个球体。
but in different times.
一些"文明"将"球体"送到地球。
Some civilization sent the Sphere on Earth
为他们创造适合他们的生物圈。
to create a biosphere suitable for them.
但是出了点问题。
But something went wrong.
但这意味着无论我们在这里做什么
But that means no matter what we do here,
我们都无法拯救地球上的人。
we won't save the people on Earth?
只剩下一个选项了。
There's only one option left,
告诉艾米这些外星细菌...
tell Amy about those extraterrestrial bacteria
...将帮助她研制疫苗。
and help her to create the vaccine.
你打算怎么做？
How do you plan to do that?
现在我们已经知道，这个球体仍会留在洞穴中直到我们重新发现它。
We know that the Sphere will remain in the cave until our time.
未来的我将会用这块碎片为艾米做手镯。
And that I will make this fragment into a bracelet for Amy.
我会给他写一条信息，告诉她如何连接"球体"。
I'll write her a message telling her how to connect the Spheres.
但在我们离开之前，艾米拿着手镯。
But Amy had the bracelet before we left.
她什么也没说。
And she didn't say anything about it.
我相信艾米会想念我的。
I believe Amy will miss me.
她会来拿手镯，
She will come for the bracelet,
早晚她都会看到这些铭文。
and sooner or later she will see these inscriptions.
剩下的就是放回零件
What's left is to put the part back
并重新调整系统。
and reconfigure the system.
否则，我们所知道的生命与人性...
Or the life that we ​​know
将永远不会出现。
will never appear.
人类也不会。
Neither will humanity.
史蒂夫! 史蒂夫！
Steve! Steve!
瑞恩计划炸毁"球体"。
Ryan is planning on blowing up the Sphere.
让我联系他
Connect me to him.
他把他的通讯关了。
He switched off his radio.
你得亲自找到他
You need to find him
并解释一切。
and explain everything.
快走，我重新打开了气闸。
Go, I've re-opened the airlock.
站住。
Stop right there.
瑞安
Ryan…
这"球体"是我们唯一的机会。
The Sphere is our only chance.
想都别想
Don't even try.
好吧, 行。
Okay. Okay.
但你的计划仍然行不通。
But your plan still won't work.
它可以。
It will.
你会知道的。
You'll see.
你想把炸弹带进洞穴。
You want to take the bomb to the cave,
你会等到"特洛伊"找到你。然后在那里炸毁"球体"和"特洛伊"。
wait for the Trojan there and blow it up along with the Sphere.
但是如果它在半路上攻击你怎么办？
But what if it attacks you on the way?
那我也会继续计划
Then I will go up
一起炸得渣都不剩
in smoke with him.
然后你的计划失败。
And you will lose.
然后，"球体"将继续为"特洛伊"创造它所需要的环境。
After all, the Sphere will continue to create the environment that the Trojan needs.
那你有什么想法？你有更好的主意吗？
What do you suggest?You got a better idea?
我们把"特洛伊"
Let's lure in the Trojan,
引进着陆器里。
into the lander,
关闭气闸然后把它炸上天。
lock the airlocks and blow it up.
给你。
Here.
大卫, 你干啥？
David, why?
为了丽塔！
For Rita.
她死了！
She died.
她还没死！
She hasn't died yet.
你疯了。
You're deranged.
我没疯。
I'm not.
在山洞里发生的那些事之后，我明白了。
After what have happened in the cave, I understand.
"特洛伊"没有杀我。
The Trojan didn't kill me,
而且它不会没有缘由地做事。
and it doesn't do anything without a reason.
它选择了我！
It chose me.
我也会帮助它。
And I will help it.
我们不应该在这里。
We weren't supposed to be here.
我们在这出现是一个错误。
We're a mistake.
你是帮助我理解这一点的人。
And you are the one who helped me understand that.
我知道我们都一样，史蒂夫！
I realized that we all are just like you, Steve.
我们不是天生的。
We weren't created right.
我们是因为"球体"的故障...
We're a malfunction of the Sphere.
但我会修复它。
But I will fix it.
大卫！ 别傻了！
David, wake up!
你不能那样帮助丽塔！
You can't help Rita like that!
她不是生来就受苦的。
She wouldn't be born to suffer,
而且她8岁也不该死！
and she will not die at the age of eight.
没有其他人会受苦，史蒂夫。
No ones else will suffer, Steve,
因为人类不曾存在过！
because there will never be any people to begin with.
人类应该有机会。 大卫。
People deserve a chance, David.
人类不曾改变过。
People don't change.
指挥部
Encounter to Mission.
这里是指挥部
快接通啊
Come in, Mission.
加油，兄弟们
Come on, guys.
这里是指挥部
Encounter to Mission.
Encounter to Mission!
这里是指挥部
理查德
Richard
史蒂夫!感谢上帝！
Steve! Thank God!
我在摄像机上看到了爆炸。
I saw the explosion on camera.
我以为你们都在爆炸中丧生了...
I thought you were all…
- 特洛伊被摧毁了。
- The Trojan's been destroyed.
瑞恩呢？
What about Ryan?
他死了。
He didn't make it.
史蒂夫。你的氧气水平下降。
Steve, your oxygen levels are dropping.
看起来像我的氧气罐被碎片扎破了。
Looks like some shrapnel pierced the tank.
我还有多少时间？
How much time do I have?
大约一小时。
-About an hour.
坚持，稍等。 我会开船下来接你。
Look, I'll land the ship and pick you up.
不。这里有风暴, 你会坠毁的。
No, there's a storm here. You'll crash.
你接下来打算怎么办？
And what are you gonna do?
我要返回洞穴,  我必须联系艾米。
I'm going to the cave.I need to contact Amy.
风暴平息后，我会尽快降落。
Land the ship as soon as the storm settles down.
祝你好运，史蒂夫。
Godspeed, Steve.
拜托,拜托别坏了
Please start working.
史蒂夫！
Steve!
艾米？
Amy?
史蒂夫！
Steve!
你在哪里？
Where are you?
我在某个地方, 在遥远的过去。
I'm somewhere in the distant past.
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
我们没有太多时间。我想我知道该如何拯救地球。
We don't have much time.I know how to save the Earth.
你是对的。
You were on the right path.
有一种机制, 可以帮助我们制造疫苗。
There's a mechanism that can help us create the vaccine.
我在这里亲眼看到了它。
I saw it here with my own eyes.
你现在能记下来吗?
-Can you write something down?
当然，当然。
Sure. Sure.
你得帮助植物细胞
You have to teach the plant cells
教它快速识别病毒的任何变种。
to quickly identify any mutation of the virus.
这是抗原配方。
Here's the antigen formula.
艾米，我曾答应过我会回来的。
Amy, I promised I'd come back to see you.
我想现在应该做不到了。
I'm so sorry.
不，史蒂夫。
No. Steve.
我只后悔一件事。
I only regret one thing…
就是我再也不能碰你了...
That I'll never hold you again
还有我们的孩子。
and our child.
我们仍然相互联系着，记得吗？
We're connected, remember?
你永远与我同在, 和我们同在。
You'll always be with me. With us.
我爱你, 爱你们俩。
I love you. Both of you.
史蒂夫
Steve.
我爱你
I love you.
史蒂夫
Steve
地球，受到了造物主的恩惠。
The Earth, O Lord,is full of God mercy.
你教给我规则
Teach me thy statutes.
,告诉我给我常识和知识。
Teach me good judgment and knowledge.
我走向歧路, 受到了报应……
Before I was afflicted I went astray.
但现在我信守你的格言。
But now have I kept thy word.
你创造了我，塑造了我。
Thy hands have made me and fashioned me.
愿你的怜悯降临于我
Let thy tender mercies come unto me,
我以此得以生存。
that I may live.